{
    "id": "fbb35cec08d84bac8ff00c0a8f3ce74c",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I didn't go to the party .................... I was feeling a bit tired.",
            "description": "The conjunction because indicates the reason for something. ",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "however",
                "although",
                "so"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d9ad4d33738044a9870e344d2d76ab01"
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you know the reason ...................... she is angry with me?",
            "description": "After reason we use that or why. Because is not used after why.",
            "answers": [
                "why",
                "because",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0a4fefba6e4441c99839f30272fbab2a"
        },
        {
            "question": "She had ...................... many children that she didn't know what to do.",
            "description": "So...that is a conjunction. Too and very cannot be followed by that-clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "too",
                "so",
                "very"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "2091f050d2d648bf94a326fc91ba11dd"
        },
        {
            "question": "We send them weekly reports ........................... they may have all the information they need.",
            "description": "The conjunctions so that and in order that are used to talk about purpose. So that is more common in an informal style. ",
            "answers": [
                "so that",
                "in order that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c5674f6283bc489691677b6703efb1ba"
        },
        {
            "question": "Send the parcel express ...................... they get it before Monday.",
            "description": "We use so that to indicate purpose.",
            "answers": [
                "so that",
                "so as to",
                "in order to",
                "provided that"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ba537c70693944d3b79aa8a073eafd53"
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you know a shop ................. they sell used cameras?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "there",
                "where",
                "wherever"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "38e67de8298f4c5389de68c2d52f108a"
        },
        {
            "question": "You may borrow my car ........................ you drive carefully.",
            "description": "All of these conjunctions are used to state conditions. ",
            "answers": [
                "as long as",
                "so long as",
                "provided that",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "edf9c97120b54f9db1246c0049f0af2a"
        },
        {
            "question": "........................ we go by bus or train, it will take at least 3 hours.",
            "description": "We can use whether ... or as a double conjunction. Its meaning is similar to 'it doesn't matter whether...or'.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "Whether",
                "If",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "47c24c87d7524bc1a56922a42d4d542f"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why is he looking at me ......................... he knew me?",
            "description": "The conjunctions as if and as though mean the same. ",
            "answers": [
                "as if",
                "as though",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c48c1ac42b3844a98313b87c54184802"
        },
        {
            "question": "..................... some people insist that smoking should be banned, others disagree with that view.",
            "description": "We use while to connect two contrasting ideas. ",
            "answers": [
                "While",
                "When",
                "As"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "40e7a7f163274cf084ea377a0f16419a"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am going out ....................... I have brushed my hair.",
            "description": "We use as soon as to suggest the idea that one event happens immediately after another.",
            "answers": [
                "as far as",
                "as soon as",
                "as long as"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "eb9da90cf1764ca8b7581ea1011434c2"
        },
        {
            "question": "No sooner had I closed my eyes, ................... the telephone rang.",
            "description": "Sooner is a comparative word. It is followed by than. ",
            "answers": [
                "when",
                "before",
                "than"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d97443daa01d4396a76ecb3f589343ab"
        }
    ]
}